Guide to the Jane Lathrop Stanford Papers SC0033B
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Correspondence, 1868-1905; Series 1; 6 Linear Feet
  - Outgoing, 1860-1905
    - 1900 Jun-Dec (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - LS to Gwendolyn Stewart. Thanks for added strength and encouragement she has given her., June 19, 1900
      - TLS to J.C. Branner - $2,000 for library books, half for economics dept., Prof. Ross., June 21, 1900
      - ALS to May Hopkins; welcome to Europe; the Passion Play; Jennie at convent; will take her to Paris; death of C. P. Huntington, 22-Aug-00
      - ALS to Mrs. D.S. Jordan; an instrument to do the will of her loved ones; solicitude for the students; witnesses the Passion Play; why she likes Kissingen, 31-Aug-00
      - ALS to May Hopkins; saw the Passion Play; can walk 5 miles; will take Jennie to Paris, 10-Sep-00
      - ALS to May Hopkins; death of Barbara Jordan; going to Italy and Egypt; visits to Exposition, 23-Sep-00
      - A. pc. S. to Mrs. D.S. Jordan. "Accept my best wishes", 2-Dec-00
      - A. pc. S. to Mrs. and Miss Miller. Best wishes for the New Year., 10-Dec-00
    - 1901 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - LS. to Achille Camerino re shipment of marble pillars from Italy, 2-Jan-01
      - A. pc. S. to Mrs. D.S. Jordan., 6-Apr-01
      - ALS to Chas. G. Lathrop - shipped books., 15-Apr-01
      - LS [photocopy] to Andrew D. White. Invitation to Berlin declined. Thanks for letter in time of need. Ross incident., May 7, 1901
      - LS [photocopy] to Andrew D. White. Ideas for Memorial Church and other buildings; architecture and statues.. Limits number of students into University, May 19, 1901
      - ALS to Lydia Hopkins - Jennie, etc., June 24, 1901
      - ALS to May Hopkins., June 29, 1901
      - A. pc. S. to Mrs. D.S Jordan. Describes sights in Europe., July 16, 1901
      - Telegram to Thos. Hubbard re. election of new secretary of Pacific Improvement Co., 14-Nov-01
      - L. to H. F. Coolidge - camp not to be removed until next June, 17-Nov-01
      - LS to Mr. Peterson - asking for job in museum for Mr. Brummett, 23-Nov-01
      - ALS to Chas. G. Lathrop - open special salary account., 30-Nov-01
      - TL to Chas. G. Lathrop - re buying Gold Bonds, 25-Dec-01
    - 1901 Dec 6 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - ALS to Mrs. D.S. Jordan, inside small book The Shadow of the Angel by Ernest Warburton Shurtleff., 6-Dec-01
    - 1902 Jan-Feb (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - ALS and encl. to May Hopkins. Reason for not "calling" in person., Jan 1, 1902
      - Tel. to Clinton Day re closing bid with New York house for $7,100, 6-Jan-02
      - TL (copy). J. L. Stanford to Emil Brugsch Bey re. antiquities purchased., 6-Jan-02
      - TL (copy) to Charles E. Hodges re. museum plans and Memorial Church construction., 6-Jan-02
      - TL (copy) to Chas. Lathrop re. investments, recovery from her operation, no outsiders to be allowed to use campus facilities, Mem. Church construction., 6-Jan-02
      - TL (copy) to Clinton Day re. construction plans [unidentified]., 10-Jan-02
      - Tel to Charles Lathrop re signing lowest bid for mechanical laboratory, 14-Jan-02
      - ALS to Mr. E. G. Hawley (?). Purchase of Mexican International 4 percent bonds., 19-Jan-02
      - Telegram to Chas. Lathrop re. payment of $14,500 to Mrs. McCann., 20-Jan-02
      - Telegram to Chas. Lathrop re. sale., 20-Jan-02
      - TL (copy) to Chas. Lathrop re. representation on Pacific Improvement Co. Board; electric light in museum., 20-Jan-02
      - LS to Mrs. Jordan glad to hear from her; returning to California by southern route, 3-Feb-02
      - coded message and translation to James Speyer. Purchase of bonds "cheaper later on.", 7-Feb-02
      - Telegram to Speyer and Co. re. funds to balance account., 20-Feb-02
      - Telegram to Speyer and Co. re. bonds., 21-Feb-02
      - Telegram to Hotel Manhattan re. express receipt., 27-Feb-02
      - Telegram to Speyer and Co. re. guaranteed 4 percent Gold bonds., 27-Feb-02
    - 1902 Mar-Dec (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - TL (copy) to M. Camerino re. mosaics for museum and church., 1-Mar-02
      - TLS to Archbishop Riordan. Matter of appointments entirely in Dr. Jordan's hands, 4-Mar-02
      - LS to M. Camerino re. mosaics., 20-Mar-02
      - TL (copy) to S. F. Leib re. law library., 20-Mar-02
      - TL (copy) to Eugene F. Loud re. Stanford post office appointment; with Loud's letter of Mar. 15 to F. W. Covey re same, 20-Mar-02
      - TLS to J.C. Branner. Postpone dedication of Church until September., 7-Apr-02
      - ALS to May Hopkins re. sea trip to Sandwich Islands., 9-Apr-02
      - LS (copy) to M. Camerino re. mosaics for church and museum., 27-Apr-02
      - LS (copy) to S. F. Leib. closes cemetery on campus, July 9, 1902
      - LS to Mr. Thomas Brown. Charles Lathrop power to attend to J. L. Stanford's financial dealings., July 28, 1902
      - ANS re: bells in library; on verso of a copy of a note from Chas. Lathrop to J. C. Branner, July 30, 1902
      - LS to Prof. Branner re cost of building; extravagance on part of professors, July 30, 1902
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Death of Mr. Nash, Mrs. Nash; deaths of other friends., 11-Aug-02
      - LS to Dr. Gardner - offers position of Chaplain., 30-Sep-02
      - TL to Benjamin I. Wheeler. Thanks for his commendation; role of church in developing the "soul germ" in the students, Sept-Oct ? 1902
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Use of horse and carriage., 17-Dec-02
      - inscribed calling card to Mrs. D.S. Jordan., 23-Dec-02
    - 1903 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - ALS to Alice Hays will arrange for her visit to University, Feb-03
      - LS (photocopy) to Andrew D. White. Recalling first meeting together in Nice. Regrets not being able to "bring about the great results in the University work that [she] ardently wish[ed] for.", March 11, 1903
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Enclosed check for Century Club., May 18, 1903
      - ALS to Chas. G. Lathrop - raise Jordan's salary., May 28, 1903
      - ALS to May Hopkins - plans trip to Yosemite, Jennie's schooling., June 22, 1903
      - LS to Mr. Clark please send on account on the Ross matter, June 27, 1903
      - LS to Susan M. Harvey. People welcome at her house., 5-Aug-03
      - LS to Mr. and Mrs. Timothy Hopkins. Keep in touch while on her long trip., 5-Aug-03
      - LS to Mr. and Mrs. Timothy Hopkins on way to Honolulu., 10-Aug-03
      - A.pc.S to Mr. and Mrs. D.S. Jordan, Best wishes for the New Year., 4-Dec-03
    - 1904 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - TLS to George Crothers re waste at the University, budgeting, prefers not to increase number of students, 7-Jan-04
      - ALS to May Hopkins re: trip, Lydia., 7-Jan-04
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Wants Japan to win War, asks them to bring Jennie with them., 20-Feb-04
      - T.L. to B.C. Blodgett re: position as prof. of music and organist at Church., June 16, 1904
      - AL (copy) to Horace Davis. Dealing with the "great mistakes made in the Ross affair;" next trustees meeting., July 14, 1904
      - LS [with written copy] to Susan L. Mills (Pres. of Mills College). Co-education an unresolved question., July 14, 1904
      - T.L. to B.C. Blodgett. Regarding salary as organist at Memorial Church if he is interested., 4-Aug-04
      - L to B. C. Blodgett. Organist at Memorial Church., 14-Aug-04
      - A.N.S. to C.G. Lathrop - Leland's scholarship money to be paid to Elsie L. Stephens., 1-Sep-04
      - Tel. ( copy ) to B.C. Blodgett. Take position of Organist at Memorial Church., 10-Sep-04
      - ALS to Mary Miller - personal, "Bertha my Maid" etc., 10-Sep-04
      - Tel. to B.C. Blodgett. Take proper care of Organ., 15-Sep-04
      - A.L. (?) to Prof. W. R. Dudley. Meeting with Judge McFarland., 18-Sep-04
      - T.L. to Wales L. Palmer. Pleasure in reading his address., 3-Oct-04
    - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - LS to Horace Davis. Dissatisfaction with President Jordan; faculty salaries, including Prof. William James., 28-Jan-05
      - ALS to May Hopkins - ill, to sail for Honolulu and Japan and clip, announcing her arrival., 15-Feb-05
      - ALS to George Crothers re address to be read at laying of the cornerstone for the library, 15-Feb-05
      - cvr. of letter to Mrs. Timothy Hopkins [no letter], 6-Mar-05
    - undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - P.S. from ALS to [May Hopkins] - illness of Mr. Nash.
      - L. to F. Patton - unable to visit Princeton.
      - ALS to Mountford Wilson - looking for book on Potassium.
      - LS to Mrs. Sherwood - Mrs. Sherwood's readings.
      - ALS to Dr. Jorgen (?) - assured Mrs. Chipman (?) should not remain.
      - ALS to Frank McCoffin. Position given to Mr. Phillips in Stanford Post Office.
      - A.L. to unknown (fragment)
      - A.L to C.P. Huntington (fragment)
    - Jordan, David Starr
      - 1891 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        - ALS to David Starr Jordan. Does not interfere in matters pertaining to University., May 6, 1891
        - L [written for Jane Stanford by secretary, G.B.] to David Starr Jordan. Hiring of music professor, Mr. Metcalf, at Stanford., Aug 10, 1891
        - ALS to David Starr Jordan. Salary of matron at Young Ladies' Dormitory., Aug 10, 1891
        - L [written for Jane Stanford by secretary, G.B.] to David Starr Jordan. Mrs. Camilla Leach and Mr. Louis Bruch (?)., Aug 21, 1891
        - ALS to David Starr Jordan. Invites the faculty to lunch., Sep 26, 1891
        - ALS to David Starr Jordan. Advises him to select one of the professors to preach next Sunday. Recommends Charles E. Hodges for employment., Oct 15, 1891
        - ALS (J. L. Stanford by sec G.B.) to David Starr Jordan. Miss Leach's letter and Roble Hall., Oct 23, 1891
      - 1892 (Box 2, Folder 13)
        - LS to David Starr Jordan. Gifts to museum from Father Cassanova. Remembers Stanford and Palo Alto., Feb 7, 1892 ?
        - ALS [with enclosure: letter from Joseph Chandler] to David Starr Jordan. Answer Chandler's questions., April 16, 1892
        - ALS to Doctor Jordan. True religion in the church; no excuse for students not attending. Sister still in critical condition., May 8, 1892
        - ALS. to Dr. and Mrs. Jordan - short description of lst year of Stanford U., July 13, 1892
        - ALS to David Starr Jordan - Reception to lady students. Sorry they could not see Dr. Jordan the previous evening., Oct 28, 1892
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Re. Mrs. Brooks and her son who wishes to enter the University., Nov 3, 1892
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Re. Miss Lake., Dec 13, 1892
        - A.N.S to Dr. Jordan. Address letters., undated, 1892
        - ALS. to D.S. Jordan - girls picking flowers in private grounds, Mrs. Sherwood's readings, and Dr. Charles of Menlo Park., circa 1892
      - 1893-1894 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - L (J. L. Stanford by sec G.B.) to David Starr Jordan. As to ex-President Harrison's lecturing at the University; suggests Senator Edmunds give commencement address; Mr. Stanford is gaining; proud of the University; the Goddard Collection., March 2, 1893
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Has instructed Mr. Anderson to collect at the dormitories., Oct 31, 1893
        - ALS (Telegram) to Pres. Jordan. Wanting him to extend courtesy to Woman's A.P. Association, April 28, 1894
        - ALS (Telegram) to Pres. Jordan. Regrets she cannot attend commencement., May 23, 1894
        - ALS (Telegram) to Pres. Jordan. Will see him after he returns from Humboldt., June 13, 1894
      - 1895 Feb-Jun (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - Telegram to Dr. Jordan, the Professors, and students of Leland Stanford University. Thanks for support., (?) 17, 1895
        - Telegram to Pres. Jordan. Main object in establishing University; declines to increase registration fees., Feb 23, 1895
        - Telegram to Pres. Jordan. Objects to soliciting subscriptions to Hildebrand Library., March 11, 1895
        - Telegram to Prof. Jordan. Arrangements for the reception., April 23, 1895
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Date for the reception., April 23, 1895
        - ALS to Pres. David Jordan. Reception to the Pioneer Graduating Class., April 26, 1895
        - Telegram to Pres. Jordan. How many are coming to reception from Palo Alto?, May 16, 1895
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Has decided not to go to England., June 27, 1895
      - 1895 Jul-Dec (Box 2, Folder 16)
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Objects to his optimistic outlook on Judge Ross' decision., July 1, 1895
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Thanks for congratulations., July 2, 1895
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Receiving many letters of congratulations but dares not yet let her soul rejoice., July 6, 1895
        - Telegram to Pres. D.S. Jordan. University exempt from inheritance tax., July 26, 1895
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Pleased with Mr. Comstock's letter; uplifted by White's letter; later will give him these letters to be read by students when she is gone., July 29, 1895
        - ALS [enclosure: letter by J.M. Stillman, June 21, 1895] to Pres. Jordan. Pleased at the evidence of Dr. Stillman's loyalty., Aug 15, 1895
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Mrs. Biddle exercised about curios given to Museum., Sep 2, 1895
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Passing on letter from George L. Burr., Sep 17, 1895
        - ALS to Pres. Jordan. Wants a position for Mrs. Clement., Sep 17, 1895
        - LS to Dr. Jordan. Good work of students in extinguishing fire; concerning Lubin prize; would like students to consider Land Loan Bill; homesick in New York., Dec 28, 1895
      - 1896 Jan-Aug (Box 2, Folder 17)
        - Telegram to Dr. Jordan. Wants list of married and unmarried professors., Jan 13, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Does not approve project to colonize Vina Ranch with colored people., Jan 21, 1896
        - Telegram to Dr. Jordan. Suspend immediately religious professorships., Jan 24, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. and Mrs. Jordan. Unite in silent prayer., Feb 12, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Has invited Rev. Anna H. Shaw to preach in Chapel., Feb 20, 1896
        - Telegram to David Jordan. Sincere thanks., March 2, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Introducing Rev. C. S. Fackenthall., March 16, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Regarding Mrs. Clements as mistress of Roble Hall., April 2, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Wants Mr. Soule retained in his position., April 7, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Does not like to be applied to for money; professors should not solicit from trustees., April 15, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Encloses letter from Alex Hogg and response., July 20, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Press must move Jan. 1; Quelle got married instead of paying his debts; has horror of debt., Aug 20, 1896
      - 1896 Oct-Dec (Box 2, Folder 18)
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Thankful he will remain at Stanford instead of going to Smithsonian Inst.; anxious about her brother Henry; has been asked to introduce Mrs. Chapman Catt., Oct 23, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Sending copies of Valentine's book on money., Oct 28, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Mr. Reed cannot accept., Oct 28, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Thinks it is unwise to have fraternity in the Hall; Barber may give trouble., Nov 3, 1896
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Thankful she has so true a helper; unable to make Swain vice-president now; wants to bring influence to bear on R.R. Co. to secure justice., Nov 24, 1896
        - ALS to Pres. and Mrs. Jordan. Their return to Stanford University., Dec 26, 1896
        - Telegram to Dr. Jordan. Does not like Prof. Miller approaching trustees for the money, 1896
      - 1897 Jan-Apr (Box 2, Folder 19)
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Sending letter from Mrs. Clements; sorry that she had to put her in such a wretched position., Jan 1, 1897
        - LS to Dr. Jordan. Correspondence to vindicate anything which might be said., Jan 11, 1897
        - Telegram to Dr. Jordan. Wants Mrs. Clements address., Jan 13, 1897
        - LS to Dr. Jordan. Objects to retention of Prof. Ross., Jan 18, 1897
        - LS to Dr. Jordan. Acknowledges tickets to lectures at Golden Gate Hall., Jan 21, 1897
        - LS to Dr. Jordan. Objects to recitation rooms in Encina Hall., April 3, 1897
        - Telegram to Dr. Jordan. Has found a man for Palo Alto Communicate., April 8, 1897
        - LS to Dr. Jordan. Wants Mr. Soule retained., April 9, 1897
        - LS to Dr. Jordan. Only professors may build houses costing less than $4,000.00 on campus., April 16, 1897
        - LS to Dr. Jordan. Prof. Stillman solely responsible for appointments of assistants; gave no encouragement to Mr. L. Booth., April 16, 1897
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Objects to dancing in Encina Hall., April 23, 1897
        - ALS to D. S. Jordan. Trip too dangerous for Dr. Jordan; his life too valuable for the future of Stanford University., Apr 28, 1897
      - 1897 May-Nov (Box 2, Folder 20)
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Transmitting address she had prepared to deliver on opening day., May 24, 1897
        - Telegram to Dr. David Starr Jordan. Trip restful and pleasant; relieved of anxiety., June 5, 1897
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Objects to proposal to realize on Market Street Railway stock for legatees; Met Mrs. Barnes in London., August 30, 1897
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Anxious when he is away as no one can take his place; staying in New York to promote settlement of estate., Oct 25, 1897
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Wants to see him for an hour; wants to know more of Mr. Hamlin; festival a success; Hildebrand dept wiped out., Nov 3, 1897
        - ALS to Dr. David Starr Jordan. Status of Jennie S. Lathrop., Nov 23, 1897
      - 1898 (Box 2, Folder 21)
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Referring to correspondence by F. W. Hyde regarding drinking water on the Quad., Feb 15, 1898
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Objects to the use of the Stanford name at a summer school in Pacific Grove [enclosed clippings]., March 22, 1898
        - LS to Dr. Jordan. Wants a recommendation for Grace Mathewson's music book., June 17, 1898
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Glad he is safely home; is presently at Lisson's Tavern., July 3, 1898
        - ALS to President Jordan. Prof. Elliot solely responsible for disbursement of fees., Sep 3, 1898
        - ALS to Dr. Jordan. Holds Prof. Elliot in high esteem., Sep 5, 1898
        - LS to Dr. Jordan. Regarding Sigma Nu matter., Oct 31, 1898
      - 1899 Mar-Apr (Box 2, Folder 22)
        - Tel. thanks for Telegram, Mar 4, 1899
        - Tel. Taylor must resign from Trustees and go home., Mar 6, 1899
        - LS. On academic freedom, Mar 23, 1899
        - LS. Encloses letter from F. Atheling, assistant in mathematics, wanting to borrow $60. [Atheling letter of Mar. 29, 1899, follows], Mar 30, 1899
        - ALS. Teachers of San Mateo may visit museum free, but objects to further extension of the courtesy, Apr 12, 1899
        - LS. Insists there must be a charge for admission to museum, Apr 24, 1899
        - LS. Returns Mr. Choate's letter; God bless him, Apr 24, 1899
        - ALS. Encloses check for $1513.60, Apr 26, 1899
      - 1899 May-Dec (Box 2, Folder 23)
        - LS. Encloses letter from P. R. Smith and copy of her reply [her reply still enclosed], May 13, 1899
        - LS. Wants a meeting of students and professors to pass resolutions for Judge Field, May 13, 1899
        - ALS. Refuses to lease land to outsiders., May 15, 1899
        - LS. Thinks he should not be present at meeting of Trustees; every student has a soul germ in need of development, May 31, 1899
        - AL. Wants to forget anxieties; is taking the cure at Bad Kissingen; wonders at happiness of peasants; glad that affair with Dr. Brown is arranged [signature cut out], July 1899
        - LS. Women students at Stanford limited to 500; Stanford students fare better than those at Oxford; enjoys the German band at Bad Kissingen, July 12, 1899
        - LS. Importance of soul development; example of Ingersoll; wants to establish a chair of ethics; Dr. Brown's position temorary, Sep 5, 1899
        - LS with typescript copy. Expansion of faculty must wait on building program, Dec 16, 1899
      - 1900 Jan-May 9 (Box 2, Folder 24)
        - LS. Thankful for his helpfulness; going to Los Angeles, 5-Jan-00
        - N to Dr. and Mrs. Jordan. Invitation to reception., 20-Jan-00
        - LS. Consigns valuable letters to his care, 2-Feb-00
        - LS. As well as ever; description of return home from trip; looking forward to Dr. Jordan's return., March 24, 1900
        - N. Extends invitation to students to a reception [includes invitation of Apr. 20, 1900], 22-Apr-00
        - ALS. Wants Mr. Nash to go on a vacation, 28-Apr-00
        - LS. Increase the income to $207,000.00 for the year; not wanting an increase to the number of students; Stanford stand ahead of all American Universities; development of soul the most essential thing in life; Stanford should aim to develop soul; Prof. Ross bringing tears to her eyes; Stanford not a political machine; Japanese immigration amount to serious proportions; Kearny incident, May 9, 1900
      - 1900 May 17-Dec (Box 2, Folder 25)
        - LS. Return home from a fatiguing trip from Vina; Prof. Ross entertaining rabid ideas; should not be retained; cannot be trusted; he is a dangerous man, May 17, 1900
        - LS. Opinion remains the same., May 23, 1900
        - TL. Wants boy's paper to have proper consideration, 29-May-00
        - LS. Missionaries in China useless; at Kissingen, going to Oberammergau; regarding a conservatory of music at Stanford; anxious about Mr. Nash, 9-Aug-00
        - LS. Will get books for department most needing them; pleasure to see buildings go up in her lifetime; professors think they want many things they can do without, 8-Oct-00
        - Tel. Secure Parliamentary papers at 1,500., 10-Oct-00
        - LS. Purchase of Parliamentary Papers authorized, 10-Oct-00
        - LS. Thoughts on the Ross affair, 14-Dec-00
      - 1901 (Box 2, Folder 26)
        - Tel. approves act, 14-Jan-01
        - Tel. declines to be further quoted in Ross affair, 25-Jan-01
        - TLS. regarding the Ross affair; sympathy for losing Barbara, 30-Jan-01
        - LS. could not have endured criticism in Ross affair without Divine support; disloyalty of Howard; expressed faith in Jordan's ability, 20-Feb-01
        - LS. admires Branner's action in Ross affair; cautious about increasing payroll; advises limitation of students to focus on quality, 25-Feb-01
        - LS. need to strengthen weak places in faculty; will allow increase in payroll, 25-Mar-01
        - Tel. consents to payroll of $230,000, 5-Apr-01
        - Tel. Take no action on salary question [original plus translation], 7-Apr-01
        - LS. refers payroll question to her brother [original plus typed copy], 9-Apr-01
        - LS. Ross affair of slight import if properly handled; no salary increases during building operations, 26-Apr-01
        - LS. advises care in selection of professors; kept in N.Y. by physical disability, 30-Sep-01
        - Typed extracts of letters re Chair of Christian Philosophy, salaries, limitation on students, 1899 Sep 5-1901 Apr 9
      - 1902 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        - ALS. her health; inviting graduates to dinner; will dedicate the church on Mar. 9, 22-Jan-02
        - TLS. approves heroic action in case of Prof. Pease; her health; respect for Dr. Bull; dedication of church; description of alumni dinner, 3-Feb-02
        - LS. payroll estimate granted; please that Prof. and Mrs. Smith are to return; public and students take the measure of professors, 24-Mar-02
        - ALS. cannot consent to extra door to Library; thinks basement rooms should be utilized, 30-Aug-02
        - ALS. introduction for Mrs. Stewart, 30-Aug-02
        - ALS. affairs at Encina must end at midnight; dances limited to two per semester, 11-Sep-02
        - LS. postpones decision on enlargement of clubhouse, 20-Dec-02
      - 1903 (Box 2, Folder 28)